

FRANCISCO PINTO SANTOS

Technical Team Lead & Junior Software architect at BISITE | PhD Student | Lecturer

23-07-1998

+34 636 627 009 franpintosantos

Salamanca, Spain@ franpintosantos@gmail.com

gandalfran

© 0000-0002-9500-9336

INTERESTS

Backend developement

Web scraping

Software engenieering

Continuous Integration

Code Generation

SKILLS

Node.js

Express.js

Vue.js

TypeScript | SQL DB

NoSQL DB

Python

Apache Kafka

Flask

Git AWS

GitHub Actions

Docker

LANGUAGES

Spanish: Native

English: Full professional competence

ABOUT ME

My background includes a Master's Degree in Software Engineering obtained at the University of Salamanca (2022), where I graduated with the highest grades and obtained first place in the promotion, as well as receiving two degree awards. I also have a Master's Degree in Smart Cities & Intelligent Buildings (2022) and a Bachelor's Degree in Computer Engineering (2020) from the University of Salamanca, where I also ranked first in the promotion and received two degree awards, as well as the SEDEA award for the best graduates at national level in the area of engineering. Currently, I work as an architect and team leader in the BISITE Research Group, and I enrich my work experience with my teaching work as a lecturer at the Pontifical University of Salamanca (UPSA), and as a freelance lecturer at the University of Salamanca (USAL) and the Society for Economic Promotion of Gran Canaria (SPEGC). My interests include the development of full-stack web applications, the area of data-science, the creation of efficient data-driven architectures and the automation of code generation.

EXPERIENCE

Technical Team Lead & Junior Software architect | BISITE Research Group

iii 01/2023 - present

Salamanca, Spain

- Coordination of planning, design and development of R&D projects within a development team (10–15 people).
- Design, coordination, and maintenance of multiple systems as main Software architect & Cloud architect.
- Code-generation system design and implementation for agile project development.
- API REST analysis and design responsible.
- Design of web scrapers and web crawlers.

Senior full-stack developer & Team lead | BISITE Research Group

1 01/2022 - 01/2023

Salamanca, Spain

- Coordination of planning, design and development of R&D projects within a small team (5-10 people).
- Code-generation system design and implementation for agile project development.
- Design and implementation of a human resources management application for the company.
- API rest development Python Flask-restx.
- Development of web scrapers and web crawlers.
- Web applications development with Vue.js, Node.js, Express.js and TypeScript.
- Design and development of ETL systems via Apache Kafka.
- Implementation of continuous integration systems with GitHub Actions.

Senior full-stack developer & Team lead assistant | BISITE Research Group

1 09/2020 - 12/2021

Salamanca, Spain

- Assistant in the coordination of planning, design and development of R&D projects.
- Complete development of the deepint Python package.
- API rest development Python Flask-restx.
- Development of web scrapers and web crawlers.
- Web applications development with Vue.js, Node.js, Express.js and TypeScript.

- Design and development of ETL systems via Apache Kafka.
 Implementation of continuous integration systems with GitHub Actions.
 Full-stack developer | BISITE Research Group
- 06/2019 09/2020 Salamanca, Spain
- Development of web scrapers and web crawlers.
- API rest Development in Java Spring Boot and Python Flask-restx.
- Web applications development with Vue.js, Node.js, Express.js and TypeScript.
- Design and development of ETL systems via Apache Kafka.
- Implementation of continuous integration systems with GitHub Actions.

Intern student during summer | BISITE Research Group

i 06/2018 - 09/2018

- Salamanca, Spain
- API rest Development in Java Spring Boot.
- Web development with Vue.js and Webpack.
- Development of web scrapers and web crawlers.
- Design and development of ETL systems via Apache Kafka.

Intern student during summer | BISITE Research Group

i 06/2017 - 09/2017

- Salamanca, Spain
- API rest Development in Java EE and Java Spring Boot.
- Web development with Vue.js and Webpack.

LECTURER EXPERIENCE

Lecturer at Master of Smart Cities | University of Salamanca

iii 01/2023 - present

- Salamanca, España
- Teaching in the area of Smart Cities Asset Management.

Lecturer | Society for the Economic Promotion of Gran Canaria (SPEGC)

i 08/2022 - 12/2022

- Salamanca, Spain
- Teaching in the subjects of introduction to artificial intelligence, Convolutional Neural Networks and Recurrent Neural Networks.

Lecturer | Pontifical University of Salamanca

i 02/2022 - 11/2022

- Salamanca, Spain
- Teaching in the subjects of database systems management, computer science fundamentals I and II.

Lecturer at Master of Internet of the Things | University of Salamanca

iii 01/2021 - present

- Salamanca, España
- Teaching in the area of IoT architectures and introduction to artificial intelligence.

EDUCATION

Ph.D. in Computer Science | University of Salamanca

iii 10/2022 - Present

Salamanca, Spain

M.Sc. in Smart Cities & Intelligent buildings | University of Salamanca

1 09/2021 - 09/2022

Salamanca, Spain

• GPA: 9.04

M.Sc. in software engineering | University of Salamanca

1 09/2020 - 09/2022

Salamanca, Spain

- GPA: 9.57
- Beneficiary of the academic excellence scholarship from the University of Salamanca.
- 6 calcifications with honors, including the master's thesis.
- Graduated as first of the promotion 2020-2022 with double end of studies award, granted by the University of Salamanca and the Faculty of Sciences of the same university.

B.Sc. in computer science | University of Salamanca

= 09/2016 - 07/2020

Salamanca, Spain

- GPA: 9.55
- Graduated as first of the promotion 2016-2020 with double end of studies award, granted by the University of Salamanca and the Faculty of Sciences of the same university.
- 25 calcifications with honors, including the bachelor's thesis.
- Beneficiary of the scholarship for collaboration with department for the 2019-2020 academic course.
- Award to the third-best academic record of the 2016-2020 promotion at national level in the field of engineering by SEDEA.
- Student representation activities for three years.

ACHIEVEMENTS

Award for the best academic record of the 2020-2022 promotion of the M.Sc. in Computer Science of the University of Salamanca.

01/2023 | Salamanca, Spain

Awarded to one of the best academic records of the 2020-2022 graduating class of the Faculty of Sciences of the University of Salamanca.

11/2022 | Salamanca, Spain

Individual mention award at Microsoft Azure hackathon organized by Viewnext IBM.

04/2022 | Salamanca, Spain

Awarded to one of the best academic records of the 2016-2020 graduating class of the Faculty of Sciences of the University of Salamanca.

11/2021 | Salamanca, Spain

Award for the best academic record of the 2016-2020 promotion of the B.Sc. in Computer Science of the University of Salamanca.

07/2021 | Salamanca, Spain

Third at the national ranking of Spain Bachelor students by SEDEA. 07/2021 | Salamanca, Spain

Member of one of the two finalist teams of the AWS hackathon organized by Viewnext IBM.

02/2020 | Salamanca, Spain

Placed as first team of Salamanca, on Google Hashcode on Everis Salamanca Hub.

02/2020 | Salamanca, Spain

Member of the winning team of the Blockchain hackathon organized by the DIGITEC project.

10/2019 | Salamanca, Spain

Member of the finalist team (Global Nominee) in the NASA Space Apps Challenge hackathon at the Everis Salamanca hub.

10/2019 | Salamanca, Spain

Member of the winning team of the smart speaker hackathon organized by Viewnext.

02/2019 | Salamanca, Spain